Zhirui Wang

↑ https://github.com/KyrieRui www.linkedin.com/in/zhirui-wang-b5b1b9194 2021 0849 6271 kyrie19960324@gmail.com https://dev.to/kyrierui https://kyrierui.github.io/ruipage/

ABOUT ME

Proficient: Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, React.JS, Flutter

Previous Experience: C/C++, C#, MySQL, Swift, Android SDK, .Net, E2E Test

Tools: Git, Unix Shell, Firebase, Cypress, Android Studio

AWS, Azure, Google Cloud

Other: Hugging Face, Automated Testing, Algorithm Engineering & Fine-Tuning

Cloud Computing, Database Management

Soft Skills: Communication and Team Work, Public Speech, Self-driven problem solving,

Self-learning and adapting new skills, Time management

Working Experience

Giv2 Limited | Test Engineer

March 2024 - Present

- Developed test code using Cypress.IO, resulting in a 30% reduction in time and cost through automation of end-to-end tests.
- Maintained the Firebase user information store and wrote scripts to query user information.
- Use Cypress Electron and Vue.JS for web automated testing.
- Created a hybrid framework from scratch to represent web pages.
- Leveraged Flutter to refactor legacy code, replace deprecated package functions and optimize performance for both web and mobile platforms.

Bay of Plenty Regional Council | AI Developer Intern

November 2023 – March 2024

- Implement machine learning models and automated scripts to optimize submission review for BOPRC and increase notification consent file review speed by 30%.
- Designed and developed an LLM model embedded in Web applications for privacy Document Q&A.
- Collaborated with the digital team with a gile development to research and implement mobile flood warning APP, the model prediction accuracy reached 70%

Victoria University of Wellington | Summer Researcher

November 2022 – February 2023

- During this summer research project, I was responsible for designing a fruit classification algorithm for the agriculture department.
- Use genetic programming, combined with spectral vibration techniques, to nondestructively classify New Zealand plums by origin and variety.

Code Club Kahurangi | Volunteer, IT Tutor

August 2022 - Oct 2022

- At Kahurangi School, teach and help children understand coding concepts by explaining logic through examples like creating some logic basic games or programming robot motion.
- Organized competitions, including robot races and rock-paper-scissors games, to evaluate the effectiveness of our teaching methods in a fun and engaging environment.
- Team discussion about the teaching plan, which means formulating the programming competition strategy and writing the handout document for student.

Public Transit Search AI Assistant | React, Python, APIs (Google Maps), Git, Unix Shell, VS Code

Dec 2023

- Team project for Tauranga BayBus official website embedded customer service ChatBot.
- Team used Agile Development, learned and delivered a Full-Stack Web App.
- Learn Python libraries skills. And program locally running LLM which can store text retrieval and similarity matching via vector data.
- Gain experience by using Google Maps APIs. Program and design Map UI for customers to quickly access information using LLM.
- Gain solid knowledge of React, HTML, CSS and other Front-End programming skills, further improving Back-End and teamwork skills.

BOP GPT | Flutter, Android SDK, Swift, API(Gradio), Git, Unix Shell, VS Code

Nov 2023

- Joined a cross-functional team of five people, successfully collaborated by implementing agile methods, resulting in a 20% improvement in on-time project delivery
- Learn to establish communication between the phone and the host via the Gradio framework API.
- Learned and accumulated a lot of experience using Flutter to develop cross-platform software.
- Gaining experience to write test scripts.

Self-created VPN server. | Azure, AWS, OpenVPN, Google clould

September 2023

- A Azure cloud server established VPN for my mother's Google Scholar access.
- Gaining skills in cloud computing, including firewalls, Linux VM, user group Settings, and bill gaining.
- The server has been running on Azure, my free student account stopped in December 2023 then moved to Google Cloud now. I shared the build process on my Dev blog.

Police department crime and robbery search database. | Postgre SQL, Git, Datalore IDE

May 2023

- Improve DB-to-DB ETL processes, increasing speed of data loading and reducing cross-database dependencies, which positively reflects on projects.
- Implement full-cycle testing for database and ETL components (unit, performance, integration, security, environment, deployment)
- Developed more than 10 tables and supported data analysis by creating multiple complex SQL queries to provide efficient decision-making for police crime management.

Wellington Bus Stop Search | Java, Maven, Git, JUnit 5, JavaFX

July 2022

- Developed a Java application to simulate the bus route display and search function for the Wellington area, based on real-world bus stop data obtained from the Metlink website.
- \bullet Convert GisPoint coordinates to X/Y 2D point coordinates. Use JavaFX Graphically plots all nodes and edges to visualize bus stop locations, allowing users to easily identify and interact with specific stations.
- Gained experience in object-oriented programming and how to write Java test scripts using JUnit5.

EDUCATION

Victoria University of Wellington

June 2021 - Nov 2023

B.S. Computer Science

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Summer Research Scholarship

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

Won \$8000 Scholarship for 4 months research project, completion of algorithm model design and finished research report.

REFERENCE

• Garry Christoffersen – Bay of Plenty Regional Council

Email: Garry.Christoffersen@boprc.govt.nz

• John Clegg – Kahurangi Code Club Coordinator

Email: john@projectx.co.nz

• Professor Qi Chen – Victoria University of Wellington

Email: qi.chen@vuw.ac.nz